<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nanoparticles on Yu-Wen Chen</title>
    <link>https://ywchen-tw.github.io/tags/nanoparticles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nanoparticles on Yu-Wen Chen</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Yu-Wen Chen </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://ywchen-tw.github.io/tags/nanoparticles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitation of glucose using Cu₂O/Ag nanoparticles probe with a smartphone-controlled portable device</title>
      <link>https://ywchen-tw.github.io/project/glucose/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ywchen-tw.github.io/project/glucose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A single-step method combining material preparation and the actual glucose measurements via the in situ growth of Cu&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O/Ag nanoparticles was reported. Mechanistically, I use glucose itself to reduce Cu&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; and Ag&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; ions that are stabilized with 3-mercaptopropionic acid and bovine serum albumin under alkaline conditions to form Cu&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O/Ag nanoparticles and produce a color change in solution due to plasmonic resonance at 400 nm, which can be related back to the concentration of glucose. This was also the research of my master thesis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitation of glucose through its manipulation of the growth of Cu₂O/Ag nanoparticles [Oral]</title>
      <link>https://ywchen-tw.github.io/publication_1/conference-glucose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ywchen-tw.github.io/publication_1/conference-glucose/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing mercury ions from polluted solution through poly-dopamine-modified Fe₃O₄ nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://ywchen-tw.github.io/project/iron_oxide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ywchen-tw.github.io/project/iron_oxide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this study, I improved the production efficiency of Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; nanoparticles by using a novel microwave synthesizer. Also, by modifying a poly-dopamine layer on the surface of nanoparticles to increase the surface area of nanoparticles, I succeeded in enlarging the Hg&lt;sup&gt;2+&lt;/sup&gt; ions adsorption capacity and releasing efficiency under hydrochloric acid of poly-dopamine-modified Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; nanoparticles and maintaining the high magnetic property of the material. The magnetic property of poly-dopamine-modified Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; nanoparticles makes it eco-friendly to reuse the material.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
